

WHERE TO FIND ME

- Yuching, Sarawak
- chesterlagan@gmail.com
- 012-8802015
- in linkedin.com/in/ chester-lagan
- Chesterlagan.github.io

INTRODUCTION

Web developer with 1+ years of experience in web design and web development. Proficient skillset in web development, web architecture planning & design, tracking & web analytics, and web security management. Always motivated, eager to acquire and be up to date on new tech skills and innovations in the industry.

EDUCATION

University of Malaysia, Sarawak (UNIMAS) I 2017-2021

Bachelor of Computer Science (with Honours) in Software Engineering

CHESTER LAGAN PARAG

Junior Web Developer

WORK EXPERIENCES

- WEB DEVELOPER IN TEGAS TECH IMMERSION PROGRAMME (TTIP) Borneo Digital PLT [11/2021 - 5/2022]
 - Designed and established user-friendly websites for clients to enable responsiveness on all devices and a pleasing user experience for visitors.
 - Devised custom web architecture by utilising web services provided Amazon Web Service for websites development and deployments.
 - Implemented improvements on production website for surge traffic management, improving the traffic load ability over 50%
 - · Formulated and enforce web security measurements to further improve the protection from DDos attacks, bruteforce attacks and Cross-site Port Attack (XSPA) attempted on the production website.
 - Designed and automated web solutions accordingly to client's requirement using tools that is time and cost effective.
 - Implemented and optimised web analytics features to all deployed websites to bring meaningful data for tracking and monitoring.
 - Proactively liaise with the IT team, creative team and Chief of Technical Officer to ensure timely and quality deliverance of projects.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (INTERN)

Softworld Software Sdn. Bhd. [01/2020 - 08/2020]

- · Developed front end website architecture and back end aspect of the web-based systems.
- Created databases for functionality using MySQL and Navicat.
- Ensured cross-platform optimization and responsiveness of system.
- Conducted testing for bugs in system codes and debugging. This ensure the system to function without errors when final product was presented to the client.
- Provided maintenance on previously delivered system.
- Involved in the development process of several main system projects. (car rental system, cleaning service system, farm billing and management system)

SKILLSETS AND CERTIFICATION

Programming skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, MySQL, PHP

Tech Toolkits

- AWS
- Airtable
- Wordpress
- Pabbly
- Elementor
- Runcloud
- Woocommerce
- Cloudflare
- Google Tag Manager
 Sendgrid Google Analytics 4
 - Evalato
- Facebook Pixel

Certification



RapidMiner Applications & Use Cases – Professional Certification.



RapidMiner Data Engineering – Professional Certification.



RapidMiner Machine Learning – Professional Certification.